[{"id":3352,"question":"Which command is used to compare the contents of two files in Ubuntu?","description":"Comparing files helps in identifying differences between versions or configurations.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'diff file1 file2'","answer_b":"Run 'compare file1 file2'","answer_c":"Type 'filecomp file1 file2'","answer_d":"Use 'diffcheck'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To compare the contents of two files, use 'diff file1 file2'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3220,"question":"How do you display the last 100 lines of a log file in Ubuntu?","description":"Displaying the last lines of a log file helps in identifying recent activity or issues.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'tail -n 100 /path/to/logfile'","answer_b":"Run 'logview -100'","answer_c":"Type 'showlog --last 100'","answer_d":"Use 'logtail'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To display the last 100 lines of a log file, use 'tail -n 100 /path/to/logfile'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":36,"question":"A virtual filesystem created dynamically by Linux that contains information about system resources is:","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"/proc","answer_b":"/boot","answer_c":"/mkdir","answer_d":"/system","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":3322,"question":"How do you change your current working directory in Ubuntu?","description":"Changing the current working directory allows you to move between different folders in the terminal.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'cd directory_name'","answer_b":"Run 'goto directory_name'","answer_c":"Type 'changedir directory_name'","answer_d":"Use 'dirchange directory_name'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To change your current working directory, use the 'cd directory_name' command.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3210,"question":"Which command allows you to change the default gateway in Ubuntu?","description":"Changing the default gateway can help direct network traffic through a different route.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo ip route add default via gateway_ip'","answer_b":"Run 'setgateway gateway_ip'","answer_c":"Type 'gwchange default'","answer_d":"Use 'netcfg default-gateway'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To change the default gateway, use 'sudo ip route add default via gateway_ip'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":726,"question":"How to list a particular Kubernetes deployment?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"kubectl info deployment my-dep","answer_b":"kubectl get deployment my-dep","answer_c":"kubectl describe deployment my-dep","answer_d":"kubectl ls deployment my-dep","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"true","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Kubernetes"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":736,"question":"How to scale a replicaset named 'foo' to 3?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"kubectl scale --replicas=3 rs/foo","answer_b":"kubectl up --replicas=3 rs/foo","answer_c":"kubectl update --replicas=3 rs/foo","answer_d":"kubectl deploy  --replicas=3 rs/foo","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Kubernetes"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":3280,"question":"Which command is used to create an encrypted partition using dm-crypt in Ubuntu?","description":"Creating an encrypted partition with dm-crypt provides strong protection for sensitive data.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'cryptsetup luksFormat /dev/sdX'","answer_b":"Run 'encrypt-partition dmcrypt sdX'","answer_c":"Type 'dmcrypt create'","answer_d":"Use 'disksecure setup'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To create an encrypted partition using dm-crypt, use 'cryptsetup luksFormat /dev/sdX'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":3252,"question":"How do you configure SSH to use a non-default port in Ubuntu?","description":"Changing the SSH port improves security by avoiding automated attacks targeting the default port.","answers":{"answer_a":"Edit '/etc/ssh/sshd_config' and change 'Port' to the desired port, then restart SSH","answer_b":"Run 'sshport change'","answer_c":"Type 'setsshport'","answer_d":"Use 'ssh-config -port'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To change the SSH port, edit '/etc/ssh/sshd_config', change the 'Port' value, and restart SSH.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":1082,"question":"If you wish to have something mounted when the server is booted in which file would you need to add it:","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"/etc/fstab","answer_b":"/etc/boot","answer_c":"/etc/grub.conf","answer_d":"/etc/boot.conf","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3219,"question":"Which command is used to create a symbolic link to a directory in Ubuntu?","description":"Creating a symbolic link helps in creating shortcuts to directories without duplicating data.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'ln -s /path/to/directory /path/to/symlink'","answer_b":"Run 'linkdir directory symlink'","answer_c":"Type 'createsymlink'","answer_d":"Use 'dirlink'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To create a symbolic link to a directory, use 'ln -s /path/to/directory /path/to/symlink'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":716,"question":"An abstraction in kubernetes which defines a logical set of pods and a policy to access them.","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"node","answer_b":"cluster","answer_c":"service","answer_d":"set","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"true","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":"A service is a grouping of pods that are running on the cluster. Services are \"cheap\" and you can have many services within the cluster.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Kubernetes"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3274,"question":"Which command is used to monitor kernel logs in real-time in Ubuntu?","description":"Monitoring kernel logs in real-time helps in debugging kernel-level issues.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'dmesg -w'","answer_b":"Run 'kernellog monitor'","answer_c":"Type 'watchkernel'","answer_d":"Use 'realtime-klog'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To monitor kernel logs in real-time, use 'dmesg -w'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":1119,"question":"How to show the working tree status ?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"git status --tree","answer_b":"git status","answer_c":"git show status","answer_d":null,"answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"true","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":"Displays paths that have differences between the index file and the current HEAD commit, paths that have differences between the working tree and the index file, and paths in the working tree that are not tracked by Git.","tip":"Just git status.","tags":[{"name":"Git"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3119,"question":"How do you remove an empty directory in Ubuntu?","description":"Removing directories helps in cleaning up unused folders in the file system.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'rmdir' followed by the directory name","answer_b":"Run 'del-folder'","answer_c":"Use 'removedir'","answer_d":"Type 'rmfolder'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To remove an empty directory in Ubuntu, use the 'rmdir' command followed by the directory name.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3218,"question":"How do you disable a user account in Ubuntu?","description":"Disabling a user account temporarily prevents the user from logging in without deleting the account.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo usermod -L username'","answer_b":"Run 'disableuser username'","answer_c":"Type 'lockaccount username'","answer_d":"Use 'userdisable username'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To disable a user account, use 'sudo usermod -L username'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3303,"question":"Which command is used to create a new alias in Ubuntu?","description":"Creating an alias can simplify complex commands by assigning them a shorter, custom name.","answers":{"answer_a":"Add 'alias alias_name='command'' to '~/.bashrc'","answer_b":"Run 'create-alias alias_name command'","answer_c":"Type 'aliasconfig add'","answer_d":"Use 'setalias -new'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To create a new alias, add 'alias alias_name='command'' to '~/.bashrc' and reload the file.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":1068,"question":"What will happen If you run the command \"init 6\" in your terminal","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"Reboot the system","answer_b":"Shut down the system","answer_c":"Enter single user mode","answer_d":"Start the system without a display manager (GUI)","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"},{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3162,"question":"Which command is used to schedule a job to run at a specific time in Ubuntu?","description":"Scheduling jobs allows for automating repetitive tasks without manual intervention.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'at time'","answer_b":"Run 'cron time'","answer_c":"Type 'schedule -t time'","answer_d":"Use 'jobset time'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To schedule a job to run at a specific time, use the 'at' command followed by the desired time.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3145,"question":"How do you display all users on the system in Ubuntu?","description":"Displaying all users helps in managing accounts and identifying existing users on the system.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'cat /etc/passwd'","answer_b":"Run 'listusers'","answer_c":"Type 'showallusers'","answer_d":"Use 'userslist'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To display all users on the system, use the 'cat /etc/passwd' command, which lists all system accounts.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3287,"question":"Which command allows you to enable packet capture on a specific network interface in Ubuntu?","description":"Capturing packets helps in diagnosing network issues and analyzing network traffic.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo tcpdump -i interface_name'","answer_b":"Run 'netcapture interface'","answer_c":"Type 'pkttrace -int'","answer_d":"Use 'capture -network'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To capture packets on a specific network interface, use 'sudo tcpdump -i interface_name'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":3170,"question":"Which command is used to compress a file using bzip2 in Ubuntu?","description":"Compressing files using bzip2 helps in saving storage space with a high compression ratio.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'bzip2 filename'","answer_b":"Run 'zip-bz filename'","answer_c":"Type 'compressbz filename'","answer_d":"Use 'bzip filename'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To compress a file using bzip2, use the 'bzip2 filename' command.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3332,"question":"How do you reboot the system in Ubuntu?","description":"Rebooting the system is needed after applying updates or changes that require a restart.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo reboot'","answer_b":"Run 'restart-system'","answer_c":"Type 'reboot-machine'","answer_d":"Use 'system-restart'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To reboot the system, use 'sudo reboot'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3169,"question":"How do you view and manage systemd services in Ubuntu?","description":"Managing services with systemd helps in controlling which services run at boot and their current status.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'systemctl'","answer_b":"Run 'servicemgr'","answer_c":"Type 'sysman'","answer_d":"Use 'srvctl'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To view and manage systemd services, use the 'systemctl' command.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3375,"question":"How do you rename a directory in Ubuntu?","description":"Renaming directories is useful for better organization and management of data.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'mv old_directory_name new_directory_name'","answer_b":"Run 'renamedir old_directory_name new_directory_name'","answer_c":"Type 'changedirname old_directory_name new_directory_name'","answer_d":"Use 'movedir old_directory_name new_directory_name'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To rename a directory, use 'mv old_directory_name new_directory_name'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3112,"question":"Which command is used to display the manual pages for other commands?","description":"Manual pages provide detailed information about various commands and their options.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'man' followed by the command name","answer_b":"Run 'manual'","answer_c":"Use 'helpme'","answer_d":"Type 'cmdinfo'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To display the manual pages for commands, use the 'man' command followed by the name of the command you want to learn about.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3365,"question":"Which command allows you to delete a user in Ubuntu?","description":"Deleting a user helps in managing system access by removing unnecessary accounts.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo deluser username'","answer_b":"Run 'removeuser username'","answer_c":"Type 'deleteuser username'","answer_d":"Use 'userdel username'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To delete a user in Ubuntu, use 'sudo deluser username'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3364,"question":"How do you display the current user's groups in Ubuntu?","description":"Displaying a user's groups helps in understanding their permissions and access rights.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'groups'","answer_b":"Run 'usergroups'","answer_c":"Type 'showgroups'","answer_d":"Use 'listgroups'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To display the current user's groups, use 'groups'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":723,"question":"Which command is used to create resources in Kubernetes?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"kubectl create -f ./my-manifest.yaml","answer_b":"kubectl deploy -f ./my-manifest.yaml","answer_c":"kubectl apply -f ./my-manifest.yaml","answer_d":"kubectl fuse -f ./my-manifest.yaml","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"true","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Kubernetes"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3363,"question":"Which command is used to enable a service to start on boot in Ubuntu?","description":"Enabling a service to start on boot ensures it is always running after the system is restarted.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo systemctl enable service_name'","answer_b":"Run 'serviceboot service_name'","answer_c":"Type 'enable-service service_name'","answer_d":"Use 'bootstart service_name'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To enable a service to start on boot, use 'sudo systemctl enable service_name'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":754,"question":"Which command will duplicate each line in a file?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"sed 'p' < filename","answer_b":"sed 'd' < filename","answer_c":"cp 'p' < filename","answer_d":"cp 'd' < filename","answer_e":"cat 'p' < filename","answer_f":"cat 'd' < filename"},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"},{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":704,"question":"What is LILO w.r.t linux?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"LILO means linux loader, which loads the kernel into memory and starts the OS.","answer_b":"LILO means linux loader, which loads the OS into memory and starts the GUI.","answer_c":"LILO means linux loader, which loads the GUI into memory so the user can see what's going on.","answer_d":"LILO means linux loader, which loads the software into memory and starts the kernel then the OS.","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":3225,"question":"Which command allows you to disable password-based SSH login in Ubuntu?","description":"Disabling password-based SSH login improves security by enforcing key-based authentication.","answers":{"answer_a":"Edit '/etc/ssh/sshd_config' and set 'PasswordAuthentication no'","answer_b":"Run 'sshconfig set password-login no'","answer_c":"Type 'disable-ssh-password'","answer_d":"Use 'ssh-set pass off'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To disable password-based SSH login, edit '/etc/ssh/sshd_config' and set 'PasswordAuthentication no'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":668,"question":"What will the following command do - $ chmod 888 file","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"It enables r,w,x premissions for all users","answer_b":"It disables r,w,x premissions for all users","answer_c":"It enables r,w,x permissions only for owner of the file","answer_d":"None of the above.","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"true","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":"We can provide the permission values in octal number system and 888 is not a valid octal number.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3347,"question":"How do you create an archive of a directory in Ubuntu?","description":"Creating an archive helps in compressing and backing up files into a single package.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'tar -czvf archive_name.tar.gz directory_name'","answer_b":"Run 'archivedir directory_name'","answer_c":"Type 'compressdir directory_name'","answer_d":"Use 'backupdir directory_name'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To create an archive of a directory, use 'tar -czvf archive_name.tar.gz directory_name'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":10274,"question":"You are configuring a Linux server to act as a DHCP server for your network. Which package provides the DHCP server functionality on most Linux distributions?","description":"Architectural decision question on setting up a DHCP server on Linux.","answers":{"answer_a":"dhcpd","answer_b":"dnsmasq","answer_c":"bind","answer_d":"iptables","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"The 'dhcpd' package, also known as ISC DHCP, provides the DHCP server functionality on most Linux distributions.","tip":"Ensure proper configuration of the DHCP server settings and IP address ranges to avoid conflicts on the network.","tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":661,"question":"Which key combination can yank a line in vi?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"yw","answer_b":"yc","answer_c":"yy","answer_d":"yl","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"true","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3366,"question":"How do you schedule a task to run every day at midnight in Ubuntu?","description":"Scheduling tasks helps in automating routine activities such as backups or updates.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'crontab -e' and add '0 0 * * * command'","answer_b":"Run 'midnightjob command'","answer_c":"Type 'daily-task schedule'","answer_d":"Use 'schedule-task 00:00 command'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To schedule a task to run every day at midnight, use 'crontab -e' and add '0 0 * * * command'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3251,"question":"How do you create a cron job that runs every 15 minutes in Ubuntu?","description":"Creating a cron job helps automate repetitive tasks such as backups or monitoring.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'crontab -e' and add '*/15 * * * * command'","answer_b":"Run 'setcron 15-min command'","answer_c":"Type 'cronjob create 15m'","answer_d":"Use 'cronsched -15'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To create a cron job that runs every 15 minutes, use 'crontab -e' and add '*/15 * * * * command'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":3279,"question":"How do you configure Ubuntu to automatically restart a service if it crashes?","description":"Configuring automatic restart for a service ensures high availability and reliability.","answers":{"answer_a":"Edit the systemd service file to add 'Restart=always' under the '[Service]' section and run 'sudo systemctl daemon-reload'","answer_b":"Run 'set-autorestart service'","answer_c":"Type 'servicereset auto'","answer_d":"Use 'autofix service'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To configure a service to automatically restart if it crashes, edit the systemd service file to include 'Restart=always' and reload the daemon.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":10274,"question":"You are configuring a Linux server to act as a DHCP server for your network. Which package provides the DHCP server functionality on most Linux distributions?","description":"Architectural decision question on setting up a DHCP server on Linux.","answers":{"answer_a":"dhcpd","answer_b":"dnsmasq","answer_c":"bind","answer_d":"iptables","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"The 'dhcpd' package, also known as ISC DHCP, provides the DHCP server functionality on most Linux distributions.","tip":"Ensure proper configuration of the DHCP server settings and IP address ranges to avoid conflicts on the network.","tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3101,"question":"How do you update all the installed packages in Ubuntu?","description":"Updating installed packages ensures that you have the latest security patches and features.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use the command 'sudo apt update && sudo apt upgrade'","answer_b":"Run 'sudo upgrade-packages'","answer_c":"Use 'apt-get install latest'","answer_d":"Click on 'Upgrade' in File Manager","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To update all installed packages in Ubuntu, use 'sudo apt update' to refresh the package list and 'sudo apt upgrade' to apply the updates.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3168,"question":"Which command is used to flush the DNS cache in Ubuntu?","description":"Flushing the DNS cache is necessary to resolve issues related to outdated or incorrect DNS information.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo systemd-resolve --flush-caches'","answer_b":"Run 'dnsflush'","answer_c":"Type 'cleardns'","answer_d":"Use 'net-clear-cache'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To flush the DNS cache, use the 'sudo systemd-resolve --flush-caches' command.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":9492,"question":"Which command is used to search for a specific string within a file in Linux?","description":"Test your understanding of searching within files in Linux.","answers":{"answer_a":"findstr","answer_b":"grep","answer_c":"searchstr","answer_d":"locate","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"true","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"The 'grep' command is used to search for a specific string within a file in Linux.","tip":"Mastering 'grep' can greatly enhance your ability to efficiently search for content within files.","tags":[{"name":"Undefined"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":9497,"question":"Which command is used to find out the disk space usage of files and directories in Linux?","description":"Test your knowledge on disk space management in Linux.","answers":{"answer_a":"space","answer_b":"du","answer_c":"diskusage","answer_d":"usage","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"true","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"The 'du' command is used to find out the disk space usage of files and directories in Linux.","tip":"Understanding 'du' can help you manage disk space efficiently by identifying space-consuming files and directories.","tags":[{"name":"Undefined"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":720,"question":"Cronjobs in kubernetes run in","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"UTC only","answer_b":"Based on NTP settings","answer_c":"Master node local timezone","answer_d":"GMT only","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Kubernetes"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3229,"question":"How do you stop and disable a service permanently in Ubuntu?","description":"Stopping and disabling a service permanently can help reduce resource usage for unnecessary services.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo systemctl stop service_name && sudo systemctl disable service_name'","answer_b":"Run 'servicestop -perm'","answer_c":"Type 'disableservice -full'","answer_d":"Use 'stopdisable srv'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To stop and disable a service permanently, use 'sudo systemctl stop service_name && sudo systemctl disable service_name'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3237,"question":"How do you resize an existing LVM logical volume in Ubuntu?","description":"Resizing an LVM logical volume allows for dynamically increasing or decreasing storage capacity.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'lvresize -L +size /dev/vg_name/lv_name'","answer_b":"Run 'lvmextend volume_name size'","answer_c":"Type 'lvresize extend'","answer_d":"Use 'lvmod -resize'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To resize an existing LVM logical volume, use 'lvresize -L +size /dev/vg_name/lv_name'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":54,"question":"What are the types of links in Linux?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"soft and hard links","answer_b":"open and close links","answer_c":"in-line and external links","answer_d":"links and highlights","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3303,"question":"Which command is used to create a new alias in Ubuntu?","description":"Creating an alias can simplify complex commands by assigning them a shorter, custom name.","answers":{"answer_a":"Add 'alias alias_name='command'' to '~/.bashrc'","answer_b":"Run 'create-alias alias_name command'","answer_c":"Type 'aliasconfig add'","answer_d":"Use 'setalias -new'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To create a new alias, add 'alias alias_name='command'' to '~/.bashrc' and reload the file.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":9494,"question":"In Linux, what command is used to change file permissions?","description":"Test your understanding of file permissions in Linux.","answers":{"answer_a":"chmod","answer_b":"chown","answer_c":"perm","answer_d":"modperm","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"The 'chmod' command is used to change file permissions in Linux.","tip":"Understanding 'chmod' is essential for managing file permissions effectively in Linux.","tags":[{"name":"Undefined"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":702,"question":"Which command can be used to display basic information about your server?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"uname","answer_b":"info","answer_c":"ls","answer_d":"show","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":687,"question":"Which command can be used by the administrator to bring the system into single user mode?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"init s","answer_b":"single","answer_c":"init","answer_d":"single s","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"},{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":690,"question":"How can we list out all currently executing background processes?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"ps -e","answer_b":"top","answer_c":"ps faux","answer_d":"proccess -aux","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"},{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":745,"question":"How to show the metrics for a given node in Kubernetes?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"kubectl ps node my-node","answer_b":"kubectl resources node my-node","answer_c":"kubectl top node my-node","answer_d":"kubectl uptime node my-node","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"true","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Kubernetes"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":682,"question":"Expand JFS in context of file system?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"Journal File System","answer_b":"Journal Failing System","answer_c":"Journal File Service","answer_d":"Journal Failing Service","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3208,"question":"Which command is used to set the system clock in Ubuntu?","description":"Setting the system clock is essential for accurate timestamps in system logs and scheduled jobs.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo timedatectl set-time \"YYYY-MM-DD HH:MM:SS\"'","answer_b":"Run 'setclock date time'","answer_c":"Type 'clockset -manual'","answer_d":"Use 'datechange set'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To set the system clock, use 'sudo timedatectl set-time' with the desired date and time.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3250,"question":"How do you add a swap partition to Ubuntu without rebooting?","description":"Adding a swap partition dynamically without rebooting helps increase system memory for demanding applications.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo mkswap /dev/sdX && sudo swapon /dev/sdX'","answer_b":"Run 'swapadd sdX'","answer_c":"Type 'addswap -partition'","answer_d":"Use 'swapon new -p'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To add a swap partition without rebooting, use 'sudo mkswap /dev/sdX' and 'sudo swapon /dev/sdX'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":3187,"question":"Which command is used to enable packet forwarding in Ubuntu?","description":"Enabling packet forwarding allows the system to route packets between different network interfaces.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo sysctl -w net.ipv4.ip_forward=1'","answer_b":"Run 'forward enable'","answer_c":"Type 'setforward on'","answer_d":"Use 'netroute forward'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To enable packet forwarding, use 'sudo sysctl -w net.ipv4.ip_forward=1'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3246,"question":"How do you recover data from a corrupted ext4 filesystem in Ubuntu?","description":"Recovering data from a corrupted filesystem is critical for preventing data loss.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo e2fsck -b superblock /dev/sdX'","answer_b":"Run 'fsrepair sdX'","answer_c":"Type 'recoverext4 /dev/sdX'","answer_d":"Use 'ext4repair -corrupt'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To recover data from a corrupted ext4 filesystem, use 'sudo e2fsck -b superblock /dev/sdX'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":738,"question":"How to delete all pods in Kubernetes matching the awk pattern1 or pattern2?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"kubectl get nodes -n myns --no-headers=true | awk '/pattern1|pattern2/{print $1}' | xargs  kubectl delete -n myns pod","answer_b":"kubectl print pods  -n myns --no-headers=true | awk '/pattern1/2|pattern2/{print $1}' | xargs  kubectl delete -n myns pod","answer_c":"kubectl print pods  -n myns --no-headers=true | awk '/pattern1/2|pattern2/{print $1}' | xargs  kubectl remove -n myns pod","answer_d":"kubectl get pods  -n myns --no-headers=true | awk '/pattern1|pattern2/{print $1}' | xargs  kubectl delete -n myns pod","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"true","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Kubernetes"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":3357,"question":"How do you find the system uptime in Ubuntu?","description":"Finding system uptime helps in determining how long the system has been running without a reboot.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'uptime'","answer_b":"Run 'sysup'","answer_c":"Type 'upstat'","answer_d":"Use 'runtime'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To find the system uptime, use the 'uptime' command.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3171,"question":"How do you restart a specific service in Ubuntu using systemctl?","description":"Restarting a service can help resolve issues without rebooting the entire system.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo systemctl restart service_name'","answer_b":"Run 'service restart service_name'","answer_c":"Type 'restart-service service_name'","answer_d":"Use 'systemd -restart service_name'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To restart a specific service in Ubuntu, use 'sudo systemctl restart service_name'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3228,"question":"How do you view the number of lines, words, and characters in a file in Ubuntu?","description":"Viewing the number of lines, words, and characters helps in analyzing text files for content or size.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'wc filename'","answer_b":"Run 'wordcount filename'","answer_c":"Type 'fileinfo -count filename'","answer_d":"Use 'linestat filename'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To view the number of lines, words, and characters in a file, use the 'wc filename' command.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3253,"question":"Which command is used to mount a network share using CIFS in Ubuntu?","description":"Mounting a CIFS network share allows access to shared files from Windows systems or other SMB-compatible servers.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo mount -t cifs -o username=user //server/share /mount/point'","answer_b":"Run 'netmount cifs server share'","answer_c":"Type 'mountcifs -server share'","answer_d":"Use 'cifsmount -net'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To mount a network share using CIFS, use 'sudo mount -t cifs -o username=user //server/share /mount/point'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":3235,"question":"How do you set kernel parameters at runtime in Ubuntu?","description":"Setting kernel parameters at runtime helps in tuning system performance without rebooting.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo sysctl -w parameter=value'","answer_b":"Run 'kernelconfig parameter=value'","answer_c":"Type 'setkernel param'","answer_d":"Use 'kernelmod -set'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To set kernel parameters at runtime, use 'sudo sysctl -w parameter=value'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":3196,"question":"Which command is used to view the file system disk space usage in Ubuntu?","description":"Checking disk space usage helps in managing storage effectively.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'df -h'","answer_b":"Run 'diskusage -all'","answer_c":"Type 'showdisk'","answer_d":"Use 'disksummary'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To view file system disk space usage, use the 'df -h' command for a human-readable summary.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3105,"question":"How do you change the current directory in Ubuntu using the terminal?","description":"Changing the directory allows you to navigate through the file system.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use the 'cd' command followed by the directory name","answer_b":"Run 'change-dir'","answer_c":"Type 'dirswitch'","answer_d":"Use 'movefolder'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To change the current directory in Ubuntu, use the 'cd' command followed by the name of the directory you want to navigate to.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3264,"question":"Which command is used to repair a Btrfs filesystem in Ubuntu?","description":"Repairing a Btrfs filesystem can help recover from metadata or data corruption.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'btrfs check --repair /dev/sdX'","answer_b":"Run 'repairbtrfs /dev/sdX'","answer_c":"Type 'btrfsfix -drive'","answer_d":"Use 'fsrepair -btrfs'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To repair a Btrfs filesystem, use 'btrfs check --repair /dev/sdX'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":20,"question":"When looking for all the processes running on a Linux system, what command should you use?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"service","answer_b":"oterm","answer_c":"ps","answer_d":"xrun","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"true","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_c","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3221,"question":"Which command allows you to show the groups that a user belongs to in Ubuntu?","description":"Showing user groups helps in understanding the permissions available to a user.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'groups username'","answer_b":"Run 'showgroups username'","answer_c":"Type 'usergroups username'","answer_d":"Use 'groupcheck username'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To show the groups that a user belongs to, use the 'groups username' command.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3361,"question":"How do you update all installed packages in Ubuntu?","description":"Updating all installed packages helps in keeping the system secure and up-to-date.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo apt upgrade'","answer_b":"Run 'updateall'","answer_c":"Type 'upgrade-packages'","answer_d":"Use 'full-upgrade'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To update all installed packages, use 'sudo apt upgrade'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3190,"question":"How do you install software from source code in Ubuntu?","description":"Installing software from source can provide more control over the installation and customization.","answers":{"answer_a":"Download the source, run './configure', 'make', and 'sudo make install'","answer_b":"Run 'src-install software'","answer_c":"Type 'sourcebuild software'","answer_d":"Use 'pkgsource software'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To install software from source, you typically download the source code, run './configure', 'make', and then 'sudo make install'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3126,"question":"Which command is used to install updates automatically in Ubuntu?","description":"Installing updates automatically helps keep your system secure and up to date.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo apt upgrade -y'","answer_b":"Run 'autoupdate'","answer_c":"Type 'update-system'","answer_d":"Use 'upgradeself'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To install updates automatically, use 'sudo apt upgrade -y'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":701,"question":"How can you count for a particular pattern occurrences in a file?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"grep −c “pattern” <file>","answer_b":"grep −k “pattern” <file>","answer_c":"cat <file> | wc -k “pattern”","answer_d":"cat <file> | wc -l “pattern”","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":648,"question":"Which command can be used to determine file type by its content?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"file","answer_b":"ls –l","answer_c":"type","answer_d":"None of the above.","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":731,"question":"How to compares the current state of the cluster against the state that the cluster would be in if the manifest was applied in Kubernetes?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"kubectl show -f ./my-manifest.yaml","answer_b":"kubectl log -f ./my-manifest.yaml","answer_c":"kubectl state -f ./my-manifest.yaml","answer_d":"kubectl diff -f ./my-manifest.yaml","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"true","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Kubernetes"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3295,"question":"How do you check the current kernel version in Ubuntu?","description":"Checking the current kernel version helps in determining if updates are necessary or troubleshooting compatibility issues.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'uname -r'","answer_b":"Run 'kernelversion'","answer_c":"Type 'kerninfo'","answer_d":"Use 'showkernel'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To check the current kernel version, use 'uname -r'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3255,"question":"How do you increase the maximum number of open file descriptors in Ubuntu?","description":"Increasing the maximum number of open file descriptors allows applications to handle more files simultaneously.","answers":{"answer_a":"Edit '/etc/security/limits.conf' and set 'nofile' limits for users","answer_b":"Run 'filemax increase'","answer_c":"Type 'setfiles -max'","answer_d":"Use 'filelimit adjust'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To increase the maximum number of open file descriptors, edit '/etc/security/limits.conf' and set 'nofile' limits for users.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":41,"question":"The partitions that are used as virtual memory when the system runs out of physical memory are known as:","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"swap partitions","answer_b":"boot partitions","answer_c":"primary partitions","answer_d":"extended partitions","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3356,"question":"Which command is used to see the hardware information of your Ubuntu machine?","description":"Viewing hardware information helps in understanding the specifications and capabilities of the machine.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'lshw'","answer_b":"Run 'hwinfo'","answer_c":"Type 'hwcheck'","answer_d":"Use 'hardinfo'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To see the hardware information, use 'lshw'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":668,"question":"What will the following command do - $ chmod 888 file","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"It enables r,w,x premissions for all users","answer_b":"It disables r,w,x premissions for all users","answer_c":"It enables r,w,x permissions only for owner of the file","answer_d":"None of the above.","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"true","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":"We can provide the permission values in octal number system and 888 is not a valid octal number.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3331,"question":"How do you install a software package using the apt package manager in Ubuntu?","description":"Installing software packages helps in adding new applications or tools to the system.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo apt install package_name'","answer_b":"Run 'pkg-install package_name'","answer_c":"Type 'addpkg package_name'","answer_d":"Use 'install software package_name'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To install a software package, use 'sudo apt install package_name'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":693,"question":"What are the respective octal value for the permission bits?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"4, 2 & 1 respectively for r, w & x.","answer_b":"4, 2 & 1 respectively for w, r & x.","answer_c":"4, 2 & 1 respectively for x, w & x.","answer_d":"4, 2 & 1 respectively for r, x & w.","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"},{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":9829,"question":"You are troubleshooting a Linux server that is running out of memory. Which command can you use to identify the processes consuming the most memory?","description":"Scenario-based question on memory troubleshooting in Linux servers.","answers":{"answer_a":"ps -eo pmem,pcpu,rss,vsize,args | sort -k 1 -nr | head -5","answer_b":"free -m","answer_c":"top","answer_d":"vmstat","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"The 'ps' command with specific flags can help list processes by memory usage, allowing you to identify memory-hungry processes.","tip":"Use tools like 'ps' with appropriate flags to get detailed information about process memory consumption.","tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":8,"question":"When do we use the GREP command","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"When we want to search for a string","answer_b":"To find a file","answer_c":"To find a directory","answer_d":"To show all directories which have the string in their name","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"true","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"},{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3357,"question":"How do you find the system uptime in Ubuntu?","description":"Finding system uptime helps in determining how long the system has been running without a reboot.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'uptime'","answer_b":"Run 'sysup'","answer_c":"Type 'upstat'","answer_d":"Use 'runtime'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To find the system uptime, use the 'uptime' command.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":1069,"question":"What will happen If you run the command \"init 0\" in your terminal","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"Shut down the system","answer_b":"Reboot the system","answer_c":"Enter single user mode","answer_d":"Start the system without a display manager (GUI)","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3300,"question":"How do you flush the DNS cache in Ubuntu?","description":"Flushing the DNS cache can resolve DNS-related issues like incorrect IP addresses being cached.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo systemd-resolve --flush-caches'","answer_b":"Run 'dnsflush'","answer_c":"Type 'flushdns'","answer_d":"Use 'cleardns -cache'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To flush the DNS cache, use 'sudo systemd-resolve --flush-caches'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":733,"question":"How to watch rolling update status of \"frontend\" deployment until completion in Kubernetes?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"kubectl rollout status --live deployment/frontend","answer_b":"kubectl rollout status -w deployment/frontend","answer_c":"kubectl rollout status -l deployment/frontend","answer_d":"kubectl rollout status -s deployment/frontend","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"true","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Kubernetes"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":671,"question":"What does the following command do? - $ chmod o-r note","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"Read permission for others is removed","answer_b":"Read permission for others is added","answer_c":"Read permission for user is added","answer_d":"Read permission for user is removed","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"true","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":"User/owner of the is reffered with ‘o’. ‘r’ means read permission bit.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":3261,"question":"How do you perform a secure wipe of a disk in Ubuntu?","description":"Performing a secure wipe ensures that all data on a disk is completely erased and cannot be recovered.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo dd if=/dev/zero of=/dev/sdX bs=1M'","answer_b":"Run 'securewipe disk sdX'","answer_c":"Type 'diskclean -secure /dev/sdX'","answer_d":"Use 'zerowipe -drive sdX'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To perform a secure wipe of a disk, use 'sudo dd if=/dev/zero of=/dev/sdX bs=1M' to overwrite all data with zeros.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":35,"question":"The /etc/shadow file in Linux is used to store:","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"filesystem information","answer_b":"various password information","answer_c":"root user shell","answer_d":"command aliases","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"true","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_b","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":49,"question":"Which of the following key combinations allows to terminate the current process in Linux shell?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"Ctrl + C","answer_b":"Ctrl + Z","answer_c":"Ctrl + A","answer_d":"Ctrl + L","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Linux"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":682,"question":"Expand JFS in context of file system?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"Journal File System","answer_b":"Journal Failing System","answer_c":"Journal File Service","answer_d":"Journal Failing Service","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":738,"question":"How to delete all pods in Kubernetes matching the awk pattern1 or pattern2?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"kubectl get nodes -n myns --no-headers=true | awk '/pattern1|pattern2/{print $1}' | xargs  kubectl delete -n myns pod","answer_b":"kubectl print pods  -n myns --no-headers=true | awk '/pattern1/2|pattern2/{print $1}' | xargs  kubectl delete -n myns pod","answer_c":"kubectl print pods  -n myns --no-headers=true | awk '/pattern1/2|pattern2/{print $1}' | xargs  kubectl remove -n myns pod","answer_d":"kubectl get pods  -n myns --no-headers=true | awk '/pattern1|pattern2/{print $1}' | xargs  kubectl delete -n myns pod","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"true","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Kubernetes"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Hard"},{"id":3185,"question":"How do you install multiple packages at once in Ubuntu?","description":"Installing multiple packages simultaneously helps in saving time during setup.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'sudo apt install package1 package2 package3'","answer_b":"Run 'installpkg package1,package2,package3'","answer_c":"Type 'apt-multi-install package1 package2 package3'","answer_d":"Use 'pkgadd list package1 package2'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To install multiple packages at once, use 'sudo apt install' followed by the package names.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"},{"id":670,"question":"Which is the invalid file name in UNIX?","description":null,"answers":{"answer_a":"LINUX","answer_b":"a.widows","answer_c":"bill .gates","answer_d":"All of the above","answer_e":"None of the above","answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"false","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"true","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":"answer_a","explanation":null,"tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"BASH"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3343,"question":"How do you create a symbolic link to a file in Ubuntu?","description":"Creating a symbolic link allows you to create a shortcut or reference to another file.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'ln -s target link_name'","answer_b":"Run 'linkfile target link_name'","answer_c":"Type 'createsym target link_name'","answer_d":"Use 'symlink target link_name'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To create a symbolic link, use 'ln -s target link_name'.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Easy"},{"id":3189,"question":"Which command allows you to set file permissions using symbolic notation in Ubuntu?","description":"Setting file permissions using symbolic notation can be more intuitive when modifying specific permissions.","answers":{"answer_a":"Use 'chmod u+x,g-w,o+r filename'","answer_b":"Run 'setperms filename'","answer_c":"Type 'permchange symbolic filename'","answer_d":"Use 'chperm -symbolic filename'","answer_e":null,"answer_f":null},"multiple_correct_answers":"false","correct_answers":{"answer_a_correct":"true","answer_b_correct":"false","answer_c_correct":"false","answer_d_correct":"false","answer_e_correct":"false","answer_f_correct":"false"},"correct_answer":null,"explanation":"To set file permissions using symbolic notation, use 'chmod' followed by the symbolic representation of permissions.","tip":null,"tags":[{"name":"Ubuntu"}],"category":"Linux","difficulty":"Medium"}]
